When there is an issue across multiple projects and you
try to diagnose using a scattered log, this could be cumbersome.
That's where the solution is having to have centralized logging.
Let's see how we can do that.
Let's say I have a project hpc2,
and I want the log from a different project also flow
into this specific project only.
So let's say I go down to the log storage,
and let's create a new log bucket, central‑logs.
Select the region and say Next and say Create bucket.
Now let me go to the other project.
In this hpc3 project, let me go down to the logs.
Here under the Logging, I'm going to select the Log router.
In the Log router on the top, click on Create sink,
give the sink name, say Next, select the sink service.
I'm going to select the service as Logging bucket.
And I have to choose a log bucket which I have created into our hpc project 2.
So I will say Use a log bucket in another project.
Now in the Sink destination,
let's copy the path of our bucket which we have created in the
project 2 and say Next. In the inclusion filter, leave it empty
so that it will include all the logs.
Say Next and say Create sink. Now our sink has been successfully created.
Now we need to do one more thing because this sink has to
write the data into our project to log bucket, so we need
to provide the IAM access.
So what I'm going to do is, so in our log sink which we have created,
click on three dots, see View sink details,
and there you see Writer identity.
So copy this writer identity and now go to the project 2 and go to the IAM.
And here, give the log writer permission to this specific
service account which we have copied.
So say Grant access, copy the name,
and under the role, select the role as Logs Bucket Writer and say Save.
Now the project 3 will be able to copy all the logs from there to the project 2,
and in the project 2 we could have the centralized log.
Similarly, we can do the same thing with the other project also.
In fact,
you can do this thing at the organization or at the folder level so that you
don't have to repeatedly do it at each and every project level.
Now if you want to watch all those logs in one central location,
let's go to the Log Explorer in the project 2.
And here in the Log Explorer, you can see the centrally
log from all the different projects.
So that's how you can set up your centralized log repository.